<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Srikrishnan Research Group @ Cornell BEE</title>
    <description>This is the website for the Srikrishnan Research Group at Cornell BEE. We study the impact of dynamic environmental hazards, particularly those intensified by climate change, on infrastructure performance and management. We are interested in a broad range of applications.
</description>
    <link>https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 21:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 21:46:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Paper on Impacts of Renewable Variability on Power Systems</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A new paper led by Elnaz Kabir, now an &lt;a href=&quot;https://elnaz-kabir.github.io/&quot;&gt;Assistant Professor in the Department of Engineering Technology &amp;amp; Industrial Distribution at Texas A&amp;amp;M&lt;/a&gt;, has &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2024.120013&quot;&gt;been published in &lt;em&gt;Renewable Energy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This paper was co-authored with several Cornell BEE collaborators, including Scott Steinschneider, M. Vivienne Liu, and C. Lindsay Anderson, and stemmed from Dr. Kabir’s postdoc with Professors Anderson, Steinschneider, and Srikrishnan at Cornell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study looked at the planned 2030 configuration of the New York State electric power system under the Community Leadership and Climate Protection Act (CLCPA), which provides one of the most ambitious plans to decarbonize a bulk power system in the world, as an exemplar for other power systems undergoing renewable-driven transitions to net-zero emissions. We looked at the co-variability of wind, solar, and hydropower to find the impacts on reliability and electricity prices. We found:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hybridization across wind, solar, and hydropower reduces the net variation in generating resources by around a half of the variability of the individual resources;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solar and wind variability result in price volatility on shorter time scales (daily and hourly), while hydropower availability is responsible for yearly annual price changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2024/02/kabir-paper-published/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2024/02/kabir-paper-published/</guid>
        
        <category>news</category>
        
        
        <category>Papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Congrats to Chloe Darnell for Her Successful M-Exam!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Chloe Darnell took her M-Exam today and successfully defended her thesis, “Uncertainty in Emissions Pathways and Earth System Dynamics: Implications for Global Mean Sea Level Rise,” despite the challenges of a building power outage. Chloe will graduate with her M.S. in Biological &amp;amp; Environmental Engineering in August before taking some well-deserved time off. Congrats, Chloe!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2023/07/chloe-m-exam/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2023/07/chloe-m-exam/</guid>
        
        <category>news</category>
        
        
        <category>People</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Nature Sustainability Paper on Air Quality Implications of Climate Mitigation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our new paper (lead author Xinyuan Huang, a Ph.D student in Civil Engineering at Penn State, and co-authored with &lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.tufts.edu/cee/people/faculty/jonathan-lamontagne&quot;&gt;Jonathan Lamontagne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://keller-lab.github.io/people.html&quot;&gt;Klaus Keller&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.weipengenergy.com/&quot;&gt;Wei Peng&lt;/a&gt;) was just &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41893-023-01133-5&quot;&gt;published in &lt;em&gt;Nature Sustainability&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, along with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41893-023-01140-6&quot;&gt;News &amp;amp; Views on the paper by Noelle E. Selin&lt;/a&gt;. An open access version is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41893-023-01133-5.epdf?sharing_token=hDwmB4jgma9aK3IRto8zDNRgN0jAjWel9jnR3ZoTv0PjQPBzmimfQxZsVEq21nizaEKyWQ5EeOyyhxm8eZWUV59i1PTX3byrFGcdU56DvKWx101bHY856T6cFSnQUtfTl9fX08usafCwrmeNCjKHoY2xIS3qSJ2eY5O-43hAzzI%3D&quot;&gt;also available&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we couple a large-scale integrated assessment model (IAM), the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gcims.pnnl.gov/modeling/gcam-global-change-analysis-model&quot;&gt;Global Change Analysis Model&lt;/a&gt;, to a reduced-form atmospheric transport and air quality model. The simplified air quality model &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/philosophy-of-science/article/abs/why-simpler-computer-simulation-models-can-be-epistemically-better-for-informing-decisions/765F7923BE9416E7FC800E4F1F7A3E34&quot;&gt;allows us to systematically explore relevant uncertainties&lt;/a&gt; using a large ensemble of future states of the world, reflecting around 15,000 different combinations of socioeconomic, technical, and agricultural trajectories. This allows us to represent many of the relevant deep uncertainties in future climate outcomes. We look at the impacts of a relatively modest global carbon tax on air quality across these states of the world as a proxy for a variety of different climate mitigation policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our key findings are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are clear air quality co-benefits in most of the world, particularly China and India, from the replacement of coal with cleaner sources of electricity generation. This is a robust finding, albeit one which is expected.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The specifics of land use changes play a major role in whether climate mitigation can result in negative outcomes. In many states of the world, a major effect of the carbon tax is the expansion of biofuel production (this is common in current IAMs). Creating the extra agricultural land for this biofuel can lead to large-scale deforestration in many countries, including Canada, Russia, and the United States. Under the default model configuration, this can result in co-harms from the generation of organic carbon, linked to deforestation from burning, particularly for countries with relatively high levels of air quality due to ongoing electric power system transitions. These co-harms tend to disappear when we use emissions factors for deforestation which are more appropriate for clear-cutting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Socio-demographics (particularly age of the exposed population) can play a large role in vulnerability to negative air quality effects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by the National Science Foundation, under grant number 2125293, and seed grant support was provided by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://iee.psu.edu/home&quot;&gt;Penn State Institute for Energy and the Environment&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aero.psu.edu/research/centers-and-institutes/institute-for-computational-and-data-sciences.aspx&quot;&gt;Institute for Computational and Data Sciences&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2023/05/air-quality-climate-paper/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2023/05/air-quality-climate-paper/</guid>
        
        <category>news</category>
        
        
        <category>Papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Paper on Structural Uncertainty and Agent-Based Modeling</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S019897152300042X&quot;&gt;a new paper&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/journal/computers-environment-and-urban-systems&quot;&gt;Computers, Environment, and Urban Systems&lt;/a&gt; on the role of structural uncertainty in agent-based models (ABMs), specifically in the context of modeling household flood risk aversion. This paper was authored with several collaborators at Pacific Northwest National Laboratory, namely Jim Yoon, Heng Wan, Brent Daniel, and David Judi, and was funded as part of the Department of Energy’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://icom.pnnl.gov/&quot;&gt;Integrated Coastal Modeling&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key question we sought to understand was the degree to which choices about the structure of agent decision rules pre-determined the range of possible outcomes that the model could produce. Structural uncertainty, which reflects the uncertainty in the mathematical and/or rule-based representation of processes, is &lt;a href=&quot;https://agupubs.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2021EF002644&quot;&gt;one of the central categories of uncertainties relevant to simulation models&lt;/a&gt;. While meta-analyses can synthesize findings across these particular models, directly assessing the role of structural uncertainty can be difficult due to complex ABM dynamics and the lack of a common simulation setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we used a common model setup to look at three different model structural variations, related to changes in how agents respond to information about flood risk. We show:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Structural changes in how flood risk changes agents’ preferences about household location can greatly influence the variability in observed outcomes such as floodplain population and housing values;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is unlikely that careful calibration will fully avoid this problem, as different outputs of interest vary in different ways across model structures; calibration may align outputs for a particular metric used for calibration&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but create overconfidence about other modeled outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We conclude by suggesting that this strong influence of model structure on ABM outcomes emphasizes the need to view ABMs as tools to understand the implications of particular theories about decision-making and social evolution (in the tradition of ABMs as simulation tools for &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1099-0526(199905/06)4:5&amp;lt;41::AID-CPLX9&amp;gt;3.0.CO;2-F&quot;&gt;generative social science&lt;/a&gt;), rather than over-interpreting projections from any particular ABM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;That is, assuming that a model structure is capable of reproducing the observations used to calibrate it! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2023/05/paper-abm-structural-uncertainty/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2023/05/paper-abm-structural-uncertainty/</guid>
        
        <category>news</category>
        
        
        <category>Papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cannon Cline Inducted Into McNair Scholars Program</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cannon Cline, sophomore in Earth &amp;amp; Atmospheric Sciences at Cornell, was inducted into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mcnairscholars.com/&quot;&gt;McNair Scholars Program&lt;/a&gt; today! The McNair Scholars Program is a federal program designed to prepare undergraduates for doctoral programs through involvement in research activities, and is aimed at diversifying the academy by focusing on first-generation students and students from traditionally underrepresented backgrounds. For his research project, Cannon will be working with the Srikrishnan Lab on understanding the risks posed by sea-level rise to coastal ecosystems. Congrats, Cannon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2023/04/mcnair-scholar-cannon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2023/04/mcnair-scholar-cannon/</guid>
        
        <category>news</category>
        
        
        <category>People</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Parin Bhaduri Awarded NSF GRFP Honorable Mention</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Congrats to Parin Bhaduri, Srikrishnan Lab Ph.D student, for being awarded honorable mention in the 2022-23 National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship program!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2023/03/nsf-grfp-parin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2023/03/nsf-grfp-parin/</guid>
        
        <category>news</category>
        
        
        <category>People</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Uncertainty Book Released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We have just released a new e-book, “Addressing Uncertainty in MultiSector Dynamics Research,” which can be accessed at &lt;a href=&quot;https://immm-sfa.github.io/msd_uncertainty_ebook/&quot;&gt;https://immm-sfa.github.io/msd_uncertainty_ebook/&lt;/a&gt;. This book is open-access (we recommend the HTML version, but a PDF version is available as well) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/IMMM-SFA/msd_uncertainty_ebook&quot;&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt;, and we intend for it to be a living document, evolving as new problems, perspectives, and techniques emerge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book was written in collaboration with several members of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://reed.cee.cornell.edu/&quot;&gt;Reed research group&lt;/a&gt; at Cornell and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://keller-lab.github.io/&quot;&gt;Keller Lab&lt;/a&gt; (formerly at Penn State, now at Dartmouth) as well as team members from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://im3.pnnl.gov/&quot;&gt;IM3 MultiSector Dynamics project&lt;/a&gt; (which also funded and supported the book’s development).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A plain language summary of the book is provided below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The presence of uncertainty challenges research across all scientific disciplines that study natural and human systems. With improvements in our understanding of interactions between these systems and increased efforts for science that bridges across singular disciplines, tackling uncertainty is both methodologically and practically very difficult. Whereas several published methods and guides already exist in the literature, there is no published guidance on how multidisciplinary research teams working on common complex problems should characterize or quantify uncertainty. The primary aim of this ebook is to provide initial guidance to teams facing these challenges and serve as a continually updated resource for researchers across disciplines that are interested in uncertainty characterization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2022/03/uc-book-release/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2022/03/uc-book-release/</guid>
        
        <category>news</category>
        
        
        <category>Papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Postdoctoral Scholar Position Open</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our group at Cornell is &lt;a href=&quot;https://academicjobsonline.org/ajo/jobs/21204&quot;&gt;looking to hire a postdoctoral scholar&lt;/a&gt; to co-lead work on uncertainty characterization for an agent-based model of human-system responses to dynamic flood risk. The position is part of the Department of Energy-funded &lt;a href=&quot;https://icom.pnnl.gov/&quot;&gt;Integrated Coastal Modeling (ICoM) project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The successful candidate will play an active role in shaping the specifics of the research and will have broad opportunities to collaborate with researchers from other universities and national laboratories. Expected qualifications include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Ph.D. in a discipline relevant to uncertainty characterization and quantification for complex systems, such as operations research, statistics, applied mathematics, or environmental engineering; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Programming skills in at least one major scientific computing language, such as Python, Julia, R, or C++;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An interest in applying quantitative methods to understanding the impacts of climate change on human systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience with coupled natural-human systems modeling and statistical techniques is preferred, though not required. The successful candidate will be expected to take on a leadership role in our group and help co-mentor undergraduates and graduate students. The position is available immediately, though the starting date can be flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on our lab group, please consult our &lt;a href=&quot;https://viveks.bee.cornell.edu/lab-manual/&quot;&gt;Lab Manual&lt;/a&gt;. For any additional information on the project (or just to reach out!), feel free to email Vivek at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:viveks@cornell.edu&quot;&gt;viveks@cornell.edu&lt;/a&gt;. Please apply at &lt;a href=&quot;https://academicjobsonline.org/ajo/jobs/21204&quot;&gt;Academic Jobs Online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2022/02/icom-postdoc-ad/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2022/02/icom-postdoc-ad/</guid>
        
        <category>news</category>
        
        
        <category>Openings</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MultiSector Dynamics Vision Report Released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://multisectordynamics.org/&quot;&gt;MultiSector Dynamics&lt;/a&gt; (MSD) Scientific Steering Group and Facilitation Team has released its &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.5825890&quot;&gt;2030 vision report&lt;/a&gt;, co-authored by Vivek! MSD is an emerging transdisciplinary research field which seeks to advance our understanding of human-Earth system interactions and their impacts on our social, economic, and engineered systems. This Vision Report is a part of the development and organization of an MSD Community of Practice, and discusses key definitions and concepts as well. A key emphasis is highlighting scientific research opportunities and approaches and needs for improving the MSD community’s research capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a webinar presenting the main themes of the report and seeking community input on February 22, 2022, from 1-3 PM ET. More information and registration are available &lt;a href=&quot;https://multisectordynamics.org/community-webinar/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2022/02/msd-vision-report/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2022/02/msd-vision-report/</guid>
        
        <category>news</category>
        
        
        <category>Papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Climate Risk Management Paper Published in Annual Reviews</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We have a new paper with &lt;a href=&quot;https://personal.ems.psu.edu/~kzk10/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Klaus Keller&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/site/caseyhelgeson/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Casey Helgeson&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-earth-080320-055847&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Annual Review of Earth and Planetary Sciences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. We review several key challenges in decision-relevant climate risk management research, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;linking the required disciplines;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;identifying relevant values and objectives;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;identifying and quantifying important uncertainties;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;resolving interactions between decision levers and the system dynamics;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;quantifying the trade-offs between diverse values under deep and dynamic uncertainties;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;communicating key information with decision-makers; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;linking decision-making needs to research design and execution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then describe avenues for overcoming these challenges to enable &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119067825.ch10&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;not only doing the science right, but doing the right science&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2021/05/climate-risk-published/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2021/05/climate-risk-published/</guid>
        
        <category>news</category>
        
        
        <category>Papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
