<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Srikrishnan Research Group @ Cornell BEE</title>
    <description>This is the website for the Srikrishnan Research Group at Cornell BEE. We study the impact of dynamic environmental hazards, particularly those intensified by climate change, on infrastructure performance and management. We are interested in a broad range of applications.
</description>
    <link>https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 16:11:10 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 16:11:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Paper in Nature on Social Cost of Methane</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We have a paper (with &lt;a href=&quot;https://cpree.princeton.edu/people/frank-errickson&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Frank Errickson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://personal.ems.psu.edu/~kzk10/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Klaus Keller&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eesa.lbl.gov/profiles/william-collins/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;William Collins&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.david-anthoff.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;David Anthoff&lt;/a&gt; published today in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41586-021-03386-6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nature&lt;/a&gt; on the social cost of methane (SC-CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;). The social cost of a greenhouse gas quantifies the net present value of emitting a unit amount of the gas (in this case, methane) into the atmosphere. This cost enables cost-benefit analyses of regulations proposing changes to limits on their emissions, which are a required part of the regulatory process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We show how several factors influence estimates of the SC-CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;, including how:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;accounting for climate-system uncertainty results in a decreased estimate compared to that used by the US government, partially due to nonlinear relationships between uncertainties related to temperature dynamics;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the sensitivity of SC-CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; to scenarios of future warming is of a comparable magnitude to that resulting from different discount rates;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the SC-CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; estimates vary little when different climate models are used, but show large sensitivities to the choice of integrated assessment model; and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the use of equity-weighting instead of constant discount rates results in large increases in the SC-CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for wealthier regions such as the US compared to regions which consume less, justifying higher mitigation expenditures in high-income countries, and these increases dwarf the decreases from climate uncertainties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper is not open access, but the News and Views perspective is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-021-00972-6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2021/04/social-cost-methane-nature-published/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2021/04/social-cost-methane-nature-published/</guid>
        
        <category>news</category>
        
        
        <category>Papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Paper in Environmental Modeling &amp; Software</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our new paper (with &lt;a href=&quot;https://personal.ems.psu.edu/~kzk10/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Klaus Keller&lt;/a&gt;) has been published in &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envsoft.2021.104978&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Environmental Modeling &amp;amp; Software&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a perfect model experiment, we demonstrate how small increases in agent-based model complexity can result in large differences in the data required to calibrate the model, as well as identifying the correct (in this case, the data-generating) model structure. This result emphasizes the importance of treating model structural uncertainty as a deep uncertainty, rather than committing to a particular parameterization. It also demonstrates the importance of leveraging multiple independent sources of information to construct sound and informative prior distributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper is open-access, and there is &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1811.08524&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a preprint&lt;/a&gt; available as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2021/02/abm-paper-published/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2021/02/abm-paper-published/</guid>
        
        <category>news</category>
        
        
        <category>Papers</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Postdoctoral Position Available</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cornell BEE is &lt;a href=&quot;https://academicjobsonline.org/ajo/jobs/17811&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;advertising&lt;/a&gt; for a postdoc! The position is part of a USDA-funded, interdisciplinary team looking at agricultural-to-energy transitions in New York State. The postdoc will be co-supervised by &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.cornell.edu/anderson1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lindsay Anderson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.cornell.edu/steinschneider/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Scott Steinschneider&lt;/a&gt;, and myself, and will have the opportunity to interact widely with other faculty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re interested in developing an energy demand model which is sensitive to nonlinear climate dynamics, as well as applying a climate stress test to a model of the New York State power system, which the postdoc would also help to develop. There are many interesting questions at the nexus of energy, water, and climate that the hired candidate would be able to explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A successful candidate would have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A Ph.D in power and energy systems or operations research;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Programming skills in at least one major programming language (&lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt; R, Python, Julia, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experience and proficiency with statistical modeling;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good communication skills and an interest and ability in developing working relationships with stakeholders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The anticipated start date is April 1, 2021, though this is flexible. To apply, go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://academicjobsonline.org/ajo/jobs/17811&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Academic Jobs Online&lt;/a&gt;. And feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto: vs498@cornell.edu&quot;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2021/01/postdoc-available-usda/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2021/01/postdoc-available-usda/</guid>
        
        <category>news</category>
        
        
        <category>Openings</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Joining Cornell BEE</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After several years at Penn State’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://eesi.psu.edu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Earth and Environmental Systems Institute&lt;/a&gt;, I’m excited to announce that I will be joining Cornell’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://bee.cals.cornell.edu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Department of Biological &amp;amp; Environmental Engineering&lt;/a&gt; as an assistant professor in July 2021. Throughout my interactions with the faculty (and some students) at BEE, I’ve been impressed with their collegiality and friendliness, not to mention the quality of their research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My group at Cornell will work on understanding the impacts of dynamic environmental hazards, particularly those influenced by climate change, on infrastructure resilience and performance. The broad goal is to provide decision support for the management of infrastructure systems under deep climate, technological, and socioeconomic uncertainty. I’m particularly interested in (i) understanding the impact of climate change on electric power system operations, (ii) developing strategies for managing flood risk, and (iii) quantifying the interactions between the human, built, and natural systems, and how these feedbacks and decisions affect system dynamics. Please &lt;a href=&quot;/contact&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt; if this seems interesting to you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving Penn State is definitely bittersweet. I’ve been lucky to call State College home, and I’ve had the opportunity to work on some very fun projects with an incredible and intellectually diverse team. I can only hope to reproduce this environment in my own research group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be affiliated with BEE immediately as a visiting assistant professor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2020/09/join-cornell/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://srikrishnan-lab.github.io/2020/09/join-cornell/</guid>
        
        <category>news</category>
        
        
        <category>Announcements</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
